Preliminary Inventory to the Joel Bernstein Papers, 1948-1979
Hoover Institution Archives
Joel Bernstein Papers,
1948-1979
80055
Bernstein, Joel, 1921-1980
24 manuscript boxes (10 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, directives, minutes, and printed matter, relating to American economic and technical assistance, the role of science and technology in underdeveloped countries, and world food supply and needs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Agency for International Development.; Economic assistance, American.; Food supply.; Technical assistance, American.; Developing countries.; United States--Foreign relations
Container List
- Chronological file (Box 1)
  - 1948-1955
  - 1956-1964 (Box 2)
  - 1967-1968
  - 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - 1970 (Box 4)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - 1973 (Box 6)
  - 1974 (Box 7)
  - 1974 (Memoranda to the Administrator and Deputy Administrator, U.S. Agency for International Development) (Box 8)
  - 1975-1976 (World Food and Nutrition Study) (Box 9)
  - 1976 (World Food and Nutrition Study) (Box 10)
  - 1976 (World Food and Nutrition Study) (Box 11)
  - 1976 (World Food and Nutrition Study) (Box 12)
  - 1976-1977 (World Food and Nutrition Study) (Box 13)
  - 1977-1978 (U.N. Study on Scientific and Technological Development) (Box 14)
  - 1979 (U.N. Study on Scientific and Technological Development) (Box 15)
- Correspondence, 1967-1974
- Speeches (Box 16)
  - 1965-1974
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
- Subject file
  - Agriculture
  - Commodity agreements
  - Economic development and commercial policy
  - Energy
  - Exchange rates and practices (Box 18)
  - Export-Import Bank
  - Foreign Service Journal
  - Inflation
  - Information material
  - Institute for Scientific and Technological Cooperation
  - International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics
  - International Development Review
  - International Monetary Fund (Box 19)
  - International Rice Research Institute
  - Italy
  - Japan
  - Korea
  - London
  - Measurement (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous briefing materials
  - Miscellany
  - Mission procedures and guidance
  - New York
  - Nigeria
  - Nigeria (Box 21)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
  - Policy decisions (Box 22)
  - Programming materials
  - Sample documentation
  - Technical assistance
  - Underdeveloped areas
  - U.N. Conference on Science and Technology for Development
  - U.S. Agency for International Development (Box 23)
  - U.S. Department of State
  - U.S. Foreign Service Institute. Senior Officers' Course
  - U.S. Foreign Service Institute. Senior Officers' Course (Box 24)
  - U.S. imports
  - U.S. International Cooperation Administration
  - U.S. Operations Coordinating Board
  - World Food and Nutrition Study